<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Einherjar</title>
    <link>https://realeinherjar.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Einherjar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/)</copyright><atom:link href="https://realeinherjar.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://realeinherjar.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://realeinherjar.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a nym. I&amp;rsquo;m a recovering academic in my mid-30s. I hold a PhD and was a faculty member in a computer science department for 5 years. My background is in computational statistics and machine learning. I&amp;rsquo;ve supervised a couple of PhD students, and taught undergraduate and graduate courses in machine learning, deep learning, statistics, data science, and programming.
I am fluent in Rust, Python, and C/C++. Due to my data science background, I also know R, SQL, and Julia.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a nym.
I&rsquo;m a recovering academic in my mid-30s.
I hold a PhD and was a faculty member in a computer science department for 5 years.
My background is in computational statistics and machine learning.
I&rsquo;ve supervised a couple of PhD students,
and taught undergraduate and graduate courses in machine learning,
deep learning, statistics, data science, and programming.</p>
<p>I am fluent in Rust, Python, and C/C++.
Due to my data science background, I also know R, SQL, and Julia.
I am comfortable in navigating almost any codebase,
disrespecting the programming language,
and also in learning new languages and frameworks.
My workflow, both personal and professional,
is heavily based on Git and GitHub:
PRs, issues, code reviews, CI/CD, project management, releases, etc.
I have solid experience with Docker, Linux and Nix environments, and cloud computing.
As a computational scientist, I am familiar with cryptography,
and I have advanced math skills.</p>
<p>I am proficient in Rust, Python, and C/C++,
supplemented by my background in data science,
I am proficient in R, SQL, and Julia.
My aptitude extends to traversing diverse codebases regardless of programming languages,
and I thrive in acquiring new languages and frameworks.
Both my personal and professional workflows heavily rely on Git and GitHub,
encompassing activities such as pull requests, issues management, code reviews,
continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD), project management
and releases.
My expertise encompasses Docker, Linux, Nix environments, and cloud computing.
Drawing from my role as a computational scientist, I am familiar with cryptography,
supported by advanced mathematical competencies.</p>
<p>During the day,
I work full-time as a senior scientific software engineer at a software company.
I co-lead a team of around 20 developers.
My role is to review PRs, develop documentation,
triage issues, and mentor junior developers.
I also take on strategic development tasks planning,
such as new features and releases.</p>
<p>I have experience in leading teams and projects,
interfacing with clients, and top management.
As volunteer work,
I have been a mentor for the Google Summer of Code program,
and board member of a non-profit open-source organization that has
NumFOCUS as a fiscal sponsor.
In fact, I was the NumFOCUS financial liaison for that organization.</p>
<p><em>Everything</em> shifted when I encountered Bitcoin.
I had arrived seeking a revolution,
and I was truly captivated by the technology and protocol behind it.</p>
<p>In my free time, I follow the technical developments of Bitcoin,
and also contribute to the ecosystem.
I have a deep understanding of the Bitcoin protocol,
lightning network, and the ecosystem in general.
I also have a good understanding of the economics and game theory behind Bitcoin.
I have knowledge about the codebases of open-source Bitcoin projects,
mainly in Rust and C/C++.</p>
<p>Check my portfolio at <a href="https://github.com/realeinherjar">GitHub</a> for some of my projects.
If you want a full CV, please contact me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
